Inventory of the F. A. Harper papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence I (Boxes 60-66)
  - Porth, A. J., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - Possony, Stefan, 1972 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - Rafferty, Gerald P., 1971-1973 (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Ream, Norman S., 1960-1972 (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - Rhine, J. B., 1965-1969 (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Richman, Frederick I., 1967-1973 (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - Ronk, Edward, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 64: 12)
  - Rottenberg, Simon, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 64: 13)
  - Royster, Vermont, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 64: 14)
  - Rueff, Jacques, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 64: 15)
  - Russell, Richard, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  - Rydenfelt, Sven, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 64: 17)
  - Sadler Report Study, 1970 (Box-folder 64: 18)
  - Sagehorn, Robert, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 64: 19)
  - Saxon, O. Glenn, 1970-1978 (Box-folder 64: 20)
  - Scaramozzino, Pasquale, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 64: 21)
  - Schaeffer, Francis A., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 64: 22)
  - Schmitz, John G., 1969-1973 (Box-folder 64: 23)
  - Schuettinger, Robert, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 64: 24)
  - Schultz, Harry, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 64: 25)
  - Schuman, Charles, 1959-1972 (Box-folder 64: 26)
  - Schureman, John C., 1970 (Box-folder 64: 27)
  - Schwartzman, Jack, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 64: 28)
  - Schweizer, Samuel, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 64: 29)
  - Scott, John H. MacCallum, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 64: 30)
  - Sennholz, Hans F., 1961-1972 (Box-folder 64: 31)
  - Sensing, Thurman, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 64: 32)
  - Sexton, Richard A., 1973 (Box-folder 64: 33)
  - Shofstall, Weldon P., 1970-1973 (Box-folder 64: 34)
  - Shuman, Charles B., 1967-1972 (Box-folder 64: 35)
  - Simonson, William, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 64: 36)
  - Smedley, Oliver, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 64: 37)
  - Smith, E. Roy, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Smith, Joe Carson, 1969 (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - Smith, Norris, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Smoot, Dan, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - Snow, Chauncey E., 1965-1972 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - Snow, John Howland, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - South Africa Foundation, 1969 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Stahl, Charles, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - Steel, William B., Jr., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - Stiefel, Werner K., 1968-1970 (Box-folder 65: 10)
  - Stillman, J. H. (Steve), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 65: 11)
  - Stoetzel, E. D., 1960-1970 (Box-folder 65: 12)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 65: 13)
  - Swift, Caroline Hyde, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 65: 14)
  - Talbot, Leonard A., 1970-1972 (Box-folder 65: 15)
  - Tax Foundation, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 65: 16)
  - Taylor, Everett, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 65: 17)
  - Thackrey, James D., 1966-1973 (Box-folder 65: 18)
  - Thalken, Thomas K., 1964-1970 (Box-folder 65: 19)
  - Thies, Richard W., 1970-1973 (Box-folder 65: 20)
  - Thin, James (Bookseller), 1971-1972 (Box-folder 65: 21)
  - Thurn, Max, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 65: 22)
  - Tidewater College, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 65: 23)
  - Todd, Vicky, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 65: 24)
  - Torrey, John D., Jr., 1970 (Box-folder 65: 25)
  - Upgren, Arthur R., 1958-1970 (Box-folder 65: 26-27)
  - Utt, James B., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 65: 28)
  - Van den Haag, Ernest, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 65: 29)
  - Van Offelen, Jacques, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 65: 30)
  - Vaux, James, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 65: 31)
  - Viscardi, Henry, 1960-1976 (Box-folder 65: 32)
    See also: Box 77, Folder 11
  - Wallis, W. Allen, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 65: 33)
  - Warden, Don, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 65: 34)
  - Ware, Richard A., 1958-1961 (Box-folder 65: 35)
  - Watts, Robert B., 1966-1971 (Box-folder 65: 36)
  - Welch, Junius P., 1971-1972 (Box-folder 65: 37)
  - Wenzlick, Roy, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 65: 38)
  - Westling, Eric, 1971 (Box-folder 65: 39)
  - Wetzel, Frank, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 65: 40)
  - Widener, Alice, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 65: 41)
  - Wiegand, G. C., 1967-1971 (Box-folder 65: 42)
  - Wilkinson, Clennell, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 65: 43)
  - Williamson, W. Rulon, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 65: 44)
  - Withers, Charles, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 65: 45)
  - Woodin, Martin D., 1959-1972 (Box-folder 66: 1)
  - Woolstein, Jarret B., 1970-1972 (Box-folder 66: 2)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, U.C. Davis, 1970 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Young, Patricia, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - Young, Robert B., 1969 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - Zeigler, John, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 66: 6)
  - Zell, Luke, 1971 (Box-folder 66: 7)
  - Zunin, Leonard M., 1970-1972 (Box-folder 66: 8)
- Correspondence II (Boxes 66-78)
  Some folders labeled as "transfer file."
  - A, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 66: 9)
  - Anderson, C. W., 1963-1969 (Box-folder 66: 10)
  - Anderson, Jerry and Laurel, 1962 (Box-folder 66: 11)
  - Andrus, Ethel Percy, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 66: 12)
  - Appel, James, 1961 (Box-folder 66: 13)
  - B-Bo, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 66: 14)
  - Br, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 66: 15)
  - Bark, Dennis L., 1966 (Box-folder 66: 16)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 66: 17)
  - Barnett, Paul S., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Belding, Don, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 67: 2)
  - Bennett, Wallace, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - Berger, René, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 67: 4)
  - Bledsoe, Thomas A., 1959-1969 (Box-folder 67: 5)
  - Boggs, John, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - Borsodi, Ralph, 1946-1976 (Box-folder 67: 7)
  - Brainard, M. W., 1967 (Box-folder 67: 8)
  - Brandt, Karl, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 67: 9)
  - Broeke, J. J. van den, 1967 (Box-folder 67: 10)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1960-1972 (Box-folder 67: 11)
  - Burger, John, 1972 (Box-folder 67: 12)
  - Burkhart, John, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 67: 13)
  - C, 1956-1972 (Box-folder 67: 14)
  - Cain, Leonard, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 67: 15)
  - California Plan, 1961 (Box-folder 67: 16)
  - Carter, Joseph J., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 67: 17)
  - Cassidy, Leonard, Jr., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 67: 18)
  - Cervantes, Lucius F., 1959-1961 (Box-folder 67: 19)
  - Chapin, Gene, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 67: 20)
  - Chodorov, Frank, 1946-1966 (Box-folder 68: 1)
  - Clark, Gordon, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 68: 2)
  - Clise, James W., 1958-1960 (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - Cluse, Robert, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Cortney, Philip, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Cowling, Donald J., 1963 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Crail, Joe, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 68: 7)
  - Crane, Jasper, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - Cravens, M. E., 1959-1962 (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - Crocker, George N., 1960-1970 (Box-folder 68: 10)
  - D, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 68: 11)
  - DeGraff, Herrell, 1946-1960 (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - DeHuszar, George B., 1959-1966 (Box-folder 68: 13)
  - DeLuca, Peter L., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 68: 14)
  - De Mille, Richard, 1959-1978 (Box-folder 68: 15)
  - Devine, Ralph J., 1960 (Box-folder 68: 16)
  - D'Evelyn, Morton, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 68: 17)
  - Dickinson, Frank, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 68: 18)
  - Doenges, James L., 1959-1973 (Box-folder 68: 19)
  - Doenges, James L., 1959-1973 (contd.) (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Dohner, Otto H., 1959-1964 (Box-folder 69: 2)
  - Driver, L. Robert, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Duhamel, P. Albert, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - Duskin, Alvin, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - E, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Effendi, Aslam, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 69: 7)
  - Erhard, Ludwig, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 69: 8)
  - F, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 69: 9)
  - Farmer, W. W., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Fellers, Bonner, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Fisher, Antony G., 1952-1969 (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - Foundation for Integrative Education, Inc., 1959-1967 (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - Fowler, Wesley F., undated (Box-folder 69: 14)
  - Fuller, Walter, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - G, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 69: 16)
  - Garshwiler, C. O., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 69: 17)
  - Geisinger, William Robert, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 69: 18)
  - Gibbons, Michael R., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - Glaser, Kurt, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Glueck, Eleanor and Sheldon, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - Goodrich, Pierre F., 1958-1972 (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Gore, James, 1967-1977 (Box-folder 70: 5)
  - Gray, David J., Jr., 1959-1961 (Box-folder 70: 6)
  - Guzman, Raymundo, 1956-1965 (Box-folder 70: 7)
  - H-He, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 70: 8)
  - Hi, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 70: 9)
  - Habsburg, Otto von, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 70: 10)
  - Hacker, Andrew, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 70: 11)
  - Hall, Clarence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 70: 12)
  - Hall, Verna, 1958-1965 (Box-folder 70: 13)
  - Hanlon, Gerald, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 70: 14)
  - Helguera, Eduardo, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 70: 15)
  - Hoiles, R. C., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 70: 16-17)
  - Holmes, Roland, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 71: 1)
  - Hoover, Allan, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 71: 2)
  - Horstman, Robert A., 1961 (Box-folder 71: 3)
  - Human Events, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 71: 4)
  - I, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 71: 5)
  - Ingebretsen, James C., 1960-1965 (Box-folder 71: 6)
  - Intercollegiate Society of Individualists, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 71: 7)
  - J, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 71: 8)
  - Jonas, Matthew, 1962 (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - K, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 71: 10)
  - Kemp, Arthur, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 71: 11)
  - Kimmel, J. S., Sr., 1966-1971 (Box-folder 71: 12)
  - Koestler, Arthur, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 71: 13)
  - Kratt, William, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 71: 14)
  - L, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 71: 15)
  - Labadie, Laurance, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 71: 16)
  - Landers, Marian, 1966 (Box-folder 71: 17)
  - Langenberg, Henry, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 72: 1-2)
  - Lavin, Charles, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Lawrence, David, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 72: 4)
  - Liggio, Leonard P., 1958-1969 (Box-folder 72: 5)
  - Love, Harry M., 1963-1977 (Box-folder 72: 6)
  - M, 1948-1972 (Box-folder 72: 7)
  - Mc, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - McConnell, James, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 72: 9)
  - McLeod, A. Neil, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 72: 10)
  - MacCallum, Spencer H., 1958-1970 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Macatee, George P. III, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Maddock, Robert A., 1972-1976 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - Martin, James, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 73: 4)
  - Meiers, Robert L., 1969-1970 (Box-folder 73: 5)
  - Meyer, Frank S., 1967-1972 (Box-folder 73: 6)
  - Mi-Mo, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - Miller, Gardner B., 1957-1962 (Box-folder 73: 8)
  - Mises, Ludwig von, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 73: 9)
  - Morley, Felix, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 73: 10)
  - Morris, James R., 1959-1969 (Box-folder 73: 11)
  - Morse, Epsie (Mrs. Robert Morse), 1966-1968 (Box-folder 73: 12)
  - Murata, Toshio, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 73: 13)
  - Myers, C. V., 1968-1972, 1978 (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - N, 1958-1973 (Box-folder 74: 2)
  - Nelson, Frederick, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 74: 3)
  - Newell, Edward C., 1966 (Box-folder 74: 4)
  - Noon, Frank, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 74: 5)
  - Norton, Robert D., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 74: 6)
  - O, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 74: 7)
  - Oliver, Michael, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 74: 8)
  - P, 1957-1973 (Box-folder 74: 9)
  - Palyi, Melchior, 1968 (Box-folder 74: 10)
  - Parks, Mercer H., 1956-1969 (Box-folder 74: 11)
  - Penteado, Jose R. W., 1964, 1970 (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - Peters, Heber Wallace, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 75: 2)
  - Pruit, John D., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 75: 3)
  - Q, 1966 (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - R, 1959-1972 (Box-folder 75: 5)
  - Reinach, Anthony, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 75: 6)
  - Reiss, Irwin H., 1962-1969 (Box-folder 75: 7)
  - Richardson, John R., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 75: 8)
  - Robert, Charles, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - Rogers, George J., 1966 (Box-folder 75: 10)
  - Rogers, James M., 1958-1972 (Box-folder 75: 11)
  - Rogge, Benjamin A., 1963-1969 (Box-folder 75: 12)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald B., 1955 (Box-folder 75: 13)
    Contains "The Story of Ralph Bunche."
  - Rothbard, Murray, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 75: 14-15)
  - S-Sh, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 75: 16)
  - Si-Sz, 1946-1973 (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - Samples, Ruhl M., 1961-1968 (Box-folder 76: 2)
  - Sargent, Dwight, 1960 (Box-folder 76: 3)
  - Sauhering, William, Jr., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 76: 4)
  - Schmidt, Emerson P., 1960-1969 (Box-folder 76: 5)
  - Sedgwick, John R., 1960-1966 (Box-folder 76: 6)
  - Shenoy, B. R., 1964-1972 (Box-folder 76: 7)
  - Smeeth, William B., 1961-1969 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - Sorokin, Pitirim A., 1959-1966 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - Stassen, John, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 76: 10)
  - Stokes, William S., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 76: 11)
  - Stone Foundation (W. Clement), 1966-1971 (Box-folder 76: 12)
  - T, 1954-1972 (Box-folder 76: 13)
  - Taylor, John M., 1963-1966 (Box-folder 76: 14)
  - Tenney, Edward A., 1959 (Box-folder 76: 15)
  - Thornley, Kerry, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 76: 16)
  - Tonomura, Hideo, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 76: 17)
  - Trippet, Byron K., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 76: 18)
  - Tuller, J. D., 1959-1969 (Box-folder 76: 19)
  - U, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - V, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 77: 2)
  - Van Sickle, John V., 1960-1972 (Box-folder 77: 3)
  - Van Wyk, Loren, 1969-1970, 1976 (Box-folder 77: 4)
  - Velasco, Gustavo R., 1947-1969 (Box-folder 77: 5)
  - Viscardi, Henry, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 77: 6)
    See also: Box 65, Folder 32
  - W, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 77: 7)
  - Wallace, De Witt, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 77: 8)
  - Wi, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 77: 9)
  - Welch, Robert, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 77: 10)
  - Wells, Harry L., 1957-1972 (Box-folder 77: 11)
  - Wells, Kenneth D., 1960-1965 (Box-folder 77: 12)
  - Wheeler, C. Julian, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - Whitman, Howard, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - Wiggins, James W., 1959-1969 (Box-folder 78: 3)
  - Wilkinson, Ernest L., 1966-1971 (Box-folder 78: 4)
  - William Volker Fund, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - Williams, Henry F., 1960 (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Winston, Ambrose P., 1962-1965 (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - Wise, Paul E., 1971 (Box-folder 78: 8)
  - X-Z, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 78: 9)
  - Younger, J. Arthur, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 78: 10)
  - Zimmerman, Carle C., 1959-1961 (Box-folder 78: 11)
  - Zimmerman, George M., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 78: 12)
  - Zube, John M., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 78: 13)
- Condolence letters on death of F. A. Harper and Marguerite Harper, 1973, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 78: 14)
  Includes 1985 notes from Harriet Harper (daughter) describing letters.
- Unfiled letters and subject files, 1960-1972 (Box-folder 78: 15)
- Swedish socialism study by Harper, 1955-1977, undated (Box 79)
  Includes manuscript drafts, notes, and research. See also: Boxes 99-100 and 53
- Bibliography on the Voluntary Society, 1953 (Box 79)
- Speeches and writings by Harper (Boxes 79-91)
  Includes lectures, conference materials, and speeches for conferences, including for the Mont Pèlerin Society.
  - 1970-1973 (Box 79)
  - 1967-1971 (Box 80)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 81)
  - 1958-1964 (Box 82)
    Includes sections of Institute of Humane Studies proposal.
  - 1957-1958 (Box 83)
    Includes Dallas Group Conference lectures and transcriptions of Dallas tapes.
  - 1957-1959 (Box 84)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 85)
    Includes Why Wages Rise material.
  - 1955-1956 (Box 86)
  - 1951-1955 (Box 87)
  - 1948-1951 (Box 88)
  - 1947-1938 (Box 89)
  - 1931-1938, undated (Box 90)
  - Agricultural economics, 1949-1945 (Box 90)
  - Book reviews, 1936-1955 (Box 90)
  - FEE lectures and miscellaneous materials, 1963, undated (Box 90)
  - Newspaper articles, 1967-1972 (Box 91)
- Cornell University materials (Boxes 91-94)
  Includes speeches and writings by Harper, lectures, course materials, research, correspondence, notes, and student work.
  - Marketing 141, 1942-1946 (Box 91)
  - 1936-1941 (Box 92)
  - 1938-1946, undated (Box 93)
    Includes Cleveland Trust Company Business Bulletin, 1943-1946.
  - 1938-1943 (Box 94)
- Speeches and writings by Harper, Free Enterprise Institute lecture materials, "Fruits of Freedom and Thorns of Slavery: A Science of Human Variation,", 1963 (Box 95)
- White House Conference on Aging (January 1961), 1955-1960 (Box 96-98)
  See also: Box 2
- Student loans, including United Student Aid Funds, 1960-1961, undated (Box 98)
- Swedish socialism study by Harper and Swedish file, 1947-1966 (Boxes 99-102)
  See also: Boxes 79 and 53. Includes glossary by Harper.
- Slides (35 mm)
  - Economic Research Counsellors, graphs, undated (Box 102)
  - F. A. Harper, Institute for Humane Studies, prepared by James M. Rogers, graphs, undated (Box 102)
- Card file, subject files, undated (Box 102)
  See also: Boxes 54-56
- Speeches and writings by Harper, reprints and pamphlets, 1945-1978 (Box 103)
  Includes pamphlets on Institute for Humane Studies.
- Cornell research tabulations (oversize), 1941-1944, undated (Box 104)
- Sound recordings
  - Shenfield talk, Professor Barry Price, 1973 January 22 (Box 105)
    Two compact sound cassettes
  - Friedrich A. von Hayek address, Institute for Humane Studies, 1977 June 10 (Box 105)
    Compact sound cassette. See also: Institute for Humane Studies miscellaneous records at the Hoover Archives, which has a copy of the recording (86002_a_0003731) that also features the remarks of other speakers at the session who refer to Hayek. See also the Friedrich A. von Hayek papers at the Hoover Archives.
  - R. C. Hoiles' life story, sound track of "Man Against the Tide,", 1968 November 22 (Box 105)
    Magnetic tape, 5 inch reel
  - Historical biography by Spencer Heath, 1961 October 14 (Box 105)
    Magnetic tape, 7 inch reel